Tony Tantisripreecha

Email: tonytan.tanapon@gmail.com | Tel: +12024984658 | Linkin | GitHub | Website |

CAREER HIGHLIGHT

With over 10 years of experience as a software engineer, researcher (Al/ML), and Computer Science lecturer, researching and developing Al applications with various techniques. Experienced in working with both small and large teams across multiple projects and companies. Able to work independently of remote locations or in office environments as needed by the company. Authorized to work in the US without sponsorship.

SKILLS

Tools: Python, Java, C, C++, C#, JS, Typescript, Golang, React, R, GO, NoSQL, SQL, .Net., Rust.

Al&ML: Deep learning, CNN, RNN, LSTM, BERT, Transformer, TensorFlow, PyTorch, Keras, Pandas,

NumPy, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Power BI, Tableau.

Others: GitHub, AWS, Linux, Ubuntu, CI/CD Pipelines, Agile, Cloud Run, Cloud Storage, Serverless.

EXPERIENCE

Researcher (AI/ML) and Computer Science lecturer

Mahidol University, Thailand

May 2018 – Jan 2024

- Partnered with a team of 10+ data scientists to develop a sentiment analysis application based on deep learning and a large language model, which boosted user engagement by 60%.
- Designed a novel term weighting algorithm named TFmeanIDF, optimized for highly imbalanced datasets, achieving a 90% improvement in predicting minority class accuracy.
- Processed Amazon datasets with 50M+ instances and over 10M+ words to **create a natural language model** using Python, pandas, and TensorFlow.
- Advised over 30 senior projects focusing on AI/ML applications, leading to project accuracy and performance improvements of 60-80%.

Researcher (AI/ML) and Computer Science lecturer

Rajamangala University of Technology Thanyaburi, Thailand

Jul 2017 - Mar 2018

- Developed a time series analysis technique for predicting US stock movement, significantly enhancing predictive accuracy by 90%.
- Conducted literature reviews on AI/ML techniques, contributing insights to research papers that have been cited over 100 times in international journals.

Software Engineer

Polar Bear Technology Group Co., Ltd, Bangkok, Thailand

Jan 2014 - Jun 2017

- Developed an automatic trading system using Java and Trader Workstation API, significantly enhancing trading efficiency and automation capabilities.
- Gathered and processed a financial dataset spanning over 10 years and including 500 stock symbols, creating a valuable resource for training financial models.
- Analyzed US stock market movements using machine learning algorithms, achieving an 80% winning rate.

EDUCATION

•	Doctor of Philosophy (Computer Science), GPA: 4.0	Nov 2010 - Sep 2016
	Kasetsart University, Thailand	
•	Master of Science in Computer Science, GPA: 3.68	Jun 2008 - May 2010
	Kasetsart University, Thailand	
•	Bachelor of Science (Computer Science), GPA 3.61 (first-class honors)	May 2004 - Apr 2008
	Khonkaen University, Thailand	